so the first step of Tomas Sol's
algorithm that we will consider is issue
so what happens during issue we take the
next instruction in program order from
the instruction queue this has to be
done in program order for register
naming to work correctly we then need to
determine where the inputs of the
instructions are going to come from are
they already in the register file or are
they going to be produced by some of the
instructions that still hasn't broadcast
its result and uh if we need to wait for
an instruction which one so there will
be some sort of rat table there we're
then going to get a free or available
reservation station of the correct kind
not that there are some reservation
stations that are for the adders some of
them are for the multiplier so if this
is an add instruction then we really
need to find an available reservation
station in front of the other if all of
the reservation stations are busy at
this point meaning they're already used
by some other instructions and those
instructions haven't left yet then we
simply don't issue anything this cycle
and in tomasulo's algorithm they were
issuing one instruction at a time so so
they they would just issue one
instruction per cycle we would put the
instruction in the reservation station
then and we will tag the destination
register of the instructions so that the
result when it's produced goes there and
also so that instructions that want that
register in the future will know which
instruction is going to produce this
file if it has already not been produced